And so what we'll be doing today as far as
for basically going forward for the rest of the workshop,
you can find all the different snapshots of
where we start and stop inside of the individual branches.
And so basically, O1 begin,
let me go ahead and add everything.
So let me check, take status, what do we change?
We change the playground.
And so the playground was for me.
So let me go ahead, kit, feature, add
live coding for essentials.
Let's see, reactive data in playground.
Okay.
So I'm gonna push that up, whoop, get push.
I haven't done this yet.
Let me do this real quick.
Boom.
All right, great.
And so check out O2, oh wait, O1 exercise.
Get push, origin, O1 exercise.
Okay.
So if you go ahead and pull down the latest changes now,
you should be able to see all the stuff that I did
inside of the playground.
Now of course, I saw that some people were coding along,
which I was really happy to see.
But of course, we're gonna actually give you a chance
to actually practice that on your own
without any guidance.
So the way that's gonna work
is what I want you to do is choose your favorite TV show
or if you don't watch TV, try movie
or basically anything that is personal to you
and basically use the index.html page that we have in there
that's already ready for you to play around with.
And I want you to go ahead and replicate what we just did.
As far as go ahead and create that app,
create a view app using the CDN,
add some reactive data tracking
to track maybe some characters on the show and whatnot.
I want you to practice using the VIF, V4.
So VIF to basically track if there are no characters,
it should show some sort of text element that says,
hey, no characters.
And then when it populates it, it swaps it out.
And then go ahead and drop in as much reactive data
as you want, again, play, have fun with this.
And yeah.
So from my end, I'm going to go ahead and open up index.html
as you all did.
And for me, I'm going to go ahead and do avatar
the last airbender.
That's the one I'm going to do.
And so inside of here, we're going to go ahead and copy over
the CDN include that I used earlier.
And then from here, we'll go ahead
and we'll start setting up the app.
So again, the convention here is div id app.
And the reason for this is because typically, the frameworks
will go ahead and render a bunch of stuff in there.
So the div, it doesn't have any semantic value
as far as from screen readers and that kind of thing.
So that's why the convention is usually to use a div.
But if for whatever reason you want to attach it to something
else, by all means feel empowered to do so.
OK, so what do we say?
We're going to create some data.
So let's say cons create app equals view.
And actually, you know what I'm going to do?
Just for the sake of showing you that they're the equivalent,
we can basically do view.createApp like this.
And then this can be a data function.
Now, I'm going to show you a new syntax
that I personally prefer to use, which
is that I'll use the arrow function for the, basically,
assigning a function to data.
And then I'll wrap the object in the parentheses.
So it basically saves a couple lines of code.
So just to show the difference on that real quick,
you'll see here this is the difference, right?
Data with the parentheses, then the actual explicit return.
This has the implicit return with the arrow.
And then we can find our data here.
So here, I can do my characters like this.
And then I'll go ahead and collapse this now,
so that we have the single column.
OK, so then we'll have four objects.
So actually, you know I'm going to go ahead and do real quick.
This is 1, 2, 3, 4.
I'm going to use a multi-cursor select by holding down command.
Might be control for Windows.
And then I'll just open up, basically, an object
so that I don't have to do that multiple times.
Great.
And then let's just save that real quick so it will auto format.
Once again, let's click through and let's add some properties.
So we'll have, basically, the name of the character.
And that's basically it.
So in this case, we have ng.
We have Zuko.
We have Tof.
And we have Katara.
All right.
So first thing first, we're going to do now is,
let's go ahead and actually render out our empty state.
So what we're going to do that is we're going to do a p element
and say, there are no characters.
And so we'll save this right now.
And let's go ahead and actually open this up inside of the browser.
So instead of playground, we'll go to index.
There you go.
There are no characters.
And then we'll have the ul here.
And just like before, we'll practice now the v4 element
that we had.
So for every character in characters, although actually,
this is surfacing a philosophical point
that I like to do when it comes to naming things.
One off errors are very common in programming.
And I find that happens a lot with spelling too.
And so the 1s plural has caught me in multiple times.
So personally, I usually like to just say that it's a list.
It's a little bit longer, but then you just
have that visual distinction.
It's a character in character list.
And then I can just render out character.name, which is great.
Although, hmm, what's happening here?
Why isn't it working?
This is a common mistake that we often
make when we're sort of creating the app this way
is because what we have to remember to do
is we need to tell view that we need to mount it.
So we're going to go ahead and run the mount command on this.
And we're going to mount it to the ID app.
And once we do that, save, refresh, uh-oh.
I broke something.
WarnSelector, why is that the case?
Well, typos.
Didn't I say something about one off errors right here?
This is a one that'll catch you off guard
because in your mind, you're thinking CSSSelector,
but you don't need the extra hashtag symbol.
Hey, there we go.
Everything's working.
So now all we've got to do, though,
is complete the exercise by saying
if characterList.length is equal to 0, then show that.
Otherwise, show this.
OK, as you can see, boom, there we go.
It's working.
If we go ahead and just go ahead and update that real quick,
you'll see there are no characters showing up.
Now, something worth noting about the vif directive,
though, is that when you use the vif directive, what view
is actually doing is, if we take a look here,
is that the UL that you have here for the else condition
does not even exist on the DOM.
So basically, the elements are being destroyed and recreated
each time you toggle that.
So as you can see here now, if we take a look at the app,
you'll notice here that the UL is president,
that the p tag is gone.
And so this is contrary to another directive
that you will see in view called v-show, which is,
I'll say, it's less popular cousin.
And that's because what v-show does
is it toggles the visibility of the element via CSS.
And so the reason you want those two different approaches
is because there are times where it might be a performance
bottleneck of destroying a list of thousands of items
and then having the DOM recreated every time someone
toggles it on and off.
And you might just want to show or hide it.
So that's where v-show, v-hide could be very useful
in those regards.
So once again, the idea here, building on what we know
and trying to make it easy for us to do
the right performance optimization.
That's a trade-off to consider when using v-f.
But again, I would say 95% of the time,
that is what you want to use.
But the moment you start thinking, oh, users
are going to be toggling this a lot,
and it might be expensive to destroy it, reach out for v-show.